JESS YOUNG

⊠ jess@soijen.com

SUMMARY

Expertise in the intersection of internal processes, technology, and data flow in business operations. I am a scientist by training and like to dissect business problems with an analytical eye.

As a professional with international experience, I am multilingual and a clear communicator to both technical and nontechnical audiences. I have lived and worked in the US, Canada and Chile.

I care about living my life with minimal negative impact to the environment and prioritize collaborating with firms committed to sustainability.

LANGUAGES

English ★★★★
Spanish ★★★★
Japanese ★★
French ★

KNOWLEDGE

Systems design Process automation
Operations mgmt. Data integration
Data analysis Project mgmt.
UI / UX Web design
Public speaking Finance

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY

HTML/CSS AutoHotKey
Salesforce Boomi
Jekyll Google Scripts
Quickbase Python
Git/Github Quickbooks
Javascript IFTTT/Zapier

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sóijen

Co-Founder: January 2018 - Present

At Sóijen we promote off-the-beaten-path areas in Patagonia through our unique products & designs. As Co-founder my role involves wearing many hats — from web design and content creation to vendor selection & management and financial planning & tracking.

Bright Power, Inc. New York, USA

Systems and Integration Specialist: January 2019 - Present Operations Associate: January 2017 – December 2018

Engineering Operations Administrator: May 2015 - December 2016

Bright Power is an engineering consulting firm that helps buildings save energy and water. My primary role on the Technology Operations team is to build internal tools, systems and integrations to automate business processes and help our employees work more efficiently.

- Designing and building integrations for our financial, CRM, project management and time tracking platforms to ensure smooth operations and flow of data between different teams.
- Implementing automation solutions using Boomi, Salesforce, Google Scripts, AutoHotKey, among other tools, to minimize manual tasks across company.
- Optimizing team workflow while implementing a new project management system to track energy audits across hundreds of buildings across the US.

Zomato Chile, SpA. Santiago, Chile

Operations Manager: August 2014 – March 2015 Content Associate: April 2014 – August 2014

Zomato is a website and app that helps users discover new restaurants. In Santiago, Chile we built a database of 8500+ restaurants from the ground up. As Operations Manager for this fast growing start-up, I focused on growing our team and developing standardized processes.

- Heading full cycle recruitment (sales, marketing, analysts) across all verticals, from entry level to senior positions. Sourcing candidates, screening, conducting 300+ interviews, training and integration of new talent. 10 new hires.
- Implementing new expense reporting system, day-to-day bookkeeping, and working with international finance team to guarantee accountability and cost-reduction.
- Developing an HR system to ensure compliance with Chilean law including safety trainings and protocols.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University Evanston, USA

Postgraduate Researcher / Teaching Assistant: 2012 – 2013

Post-graduate studies and research in physical chemistry. The focus of my research was understanding the reactions of organic aerosol particles in the atmosphere, and their consequences in climate change. In addition I taught an Organic Chemistry laboratory course and mentored undergraduate students pursuing career in sciences.

McGill University Montreal, Canada

B.Sc. in Chemistry, First Class Honors: 2007 – 2011 (GPA: 3.64/4.00)